Today, we're going to be talking about road cranks.
This can be a great upgrade to any road bike out there.
One of the top names in the business, of course, is Shimano.
Shimano is one of the companies that really is a pioneering company for both lightweight, strength, durability.
With this particular crank we're going to look at today is their top-of-the-line Dura-Ace crank.
What I've got here is a very interesting cutaway which really shows how they get that lightweight but yet extremely stiff and strong crank.
Again, to distribute that power from our pedals now right through to the drive crank to propel us froward quicker.
They made the entire crank hollow, all this being done while it's done in a casting process.
We've also made the axle integrated into the crank arm itself, makes for a much stronger, much larger axle.
And they've made the bearings that go into the frame much larger because they now sit it outside of the frame.
All of this adds up to extreme stiffness, strength, and a great riding crank that can make a big difference in your riding and your power.